Francis Tao

8688 Hazelbridge Way, Richmond, BC V6X0R6 | P: 778-681-6828 | E: ty199695@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub

Professional Summary

A diligent and ambitious professional with expertise in data analytics, passion in machine learning, exceptional communication skills and multilingual ability. A vast skill set of statistical inferences, time series analysis, predictive analysis and data visualization..

Skills

Database: PostgreSql, MySQL, T-SQL, SSMSStatistical Programming: Python, SAS, RStudioData Visualization: Tableau, Power BI, Matplotlib, SeabornData Analytics and Science: Pandas, Numpy, Sklearn

Statistical Topics: Sampling, Hypothesis Testing, A/B Testing

Others: Excel, Access, Outlook, Slack, Jira, HubSpot, SharePoint, Azure DevOps

Work History

RecycleSmart Richmond, BC

 Data Coordinator
 11/2021 – 12/2022

- Pull the data from **Microsoft SQL Server**, generate 250+/3300+ customized/standard waste diversion reports monthly in **Excel** and present insights of recycling data through **Power Query** and **Power BI** dashboard.
- Clean and transform over 8300 rows of customers/vendors' addresses with **Pandas**, build **Python** validation tools to automate the process by utilizing CanadaPost/BingMap API, computing textual similarity using **theFuzz/Levenshtein Distance** with 75.1% accuracy, converting kmz file to json and creating region/neighborhood codes based on **Polygon** geospatial analysis.
- Write **SQL** query and utilize **Power Query/Power BI** to transform the data and create visualizations which help to address 17.51% of uneven vendor lines and 106.7k invoice discrepancy for a single agreement type from Jun 2021 to Jun 2022.
- Reduce the monthly waste diversion audit workload by an average of 66.2% over the past 12 months by creating a pipeline
 including cleansing data in SQL Server and leveraging libraries re, Pandas, dateutil.parser, datetime, calendar and self def func
 in Jupyter Python.
- Automate the data migration process of generating over 15k vendor purchase contract lines' unique key, unit price, region code
 and product id through the entire ETL in SQL server(CTE, Subquery, Join, Concat, Dense_Rank, Case When) and
 Python(lambda, pandas) for new ERP(Dynamics 365) system.

ehsAl Vancouver, BC

Data Labelling Analyst

02/2021 – 10/2021

Process EHS documents and conduct language analysis including citations language labelling splitting and classifications to

- Process EHS documents and conduct language analysis including citations, language labelling, splitting, and classifications to feed the NLP model.
- Develop internal QA survey, evaluate the employees' work performance by tracking workflow in **Jira** and analysing assignments including trend prediction based on visualization through **Power BI/Excel Query**, **Pivot**, Charts, **Python Pandas**, Matplotlib, **NumPy**, **Seaborn** and improve the task accuracy by 10% within 6mo.

Providence Health CareVancouver, BCData Quality Clerk01/2020 – 06/2020

- Assist end-users with registration-related processes, liaise with various departments and escalate problems.
- Extract, sort and aggregate data using **SQL** and verify them from client registry/clinical information reports to maintain data integrity and to ensure compliance with high accuracy of above 85%.

ECCO Shoes CanadaRichmond, BC *Brand Ambassador*11/2019 – 10/2021

- Greet customers, help to find the wanted shoes, fix the displays and resolve the return and exchange issues.
- Generate more than \$1500 in weekly sales with successful marketing, sales and customer relations approaches.

Personal Projects

Bike Share Demand Prediction (Link) – 0.4075 RMSLE(301/3243 on Kaggle, top 9%); Data manipulation with **Pandas, NumPy** and datetime; Histogram, scatterplot and bars visualization with **matplotlib**; Modelling and training with **Train_Test_Split**, **LinearRegression**, **RandomForestRegressor** and **XgBoost**.

Heart Disease Prediction (Link) – GridSearchCV Logistic Regressoin with 88.5% accuracy; 303 rows of data; Barplot, scatterplot and heatmap by matplotlib and seaborn; Modelling and training with LogisticRegression, KNeighborsClassifier. RandomForestClassifier and DecisionTreeClassifier; Hypertuning using RandomizeSearchCV and GridSearchCV

Voluntary Experience

Quest Food Exchange

Vancouver, BC 05/2019 - 07/2019

Office Assistant Volunteer Excel data entry and update referral clients' information into spreadsheet over 2800 rows for 2000+ organizations.

Greater Vancouver Food Bank

Vancouver, BC 11/2021

Cleaner

Grocery shelf cleaning

Education

The University of British Columbia

Vancouver, BC

Bachelor of Science, Statistics

05/2019

Dean's List 2016 - 2017; Member of Golden Key Society: Top 15% in faculty; Graduated with 82%

Certification

- (1). Data Analyst with Python
- (2). MCSA: SQL 2016 Database Development
- (3). Tableau Desktop Specialist
- (4). SAS Certified Specialist: Base Programming
- (5). Data Science Professional Certificate